

CONTACT

- +91-7776991455
- ✓ ntnadam@live.com
- Solapur, Maharashtra, India
- https://www.linkedin.com/in/nitin-adam-a9597b126

EDUCATION

2016-2019 WALCHAND COLLEGE OF ENGINEERING, SANGLI

- BTech in Electrical
- CGPA: 9.07/10

2013 - 2016

GOVERNMENT POLYTECHNIC SOLAPUR

- Diploma in Electrical
- Percentage: 91.45%

2003 - 2013

DAYANAND KASHINATH ASAWA, HIGH SCHOOL, SOLAPUR

- General Science
- Percentage: 87.82%

SKILLS

- Project Management
- Public Relations
- Teamwork
- Quick Learner
- Time Management
- Leadership
- Effective Communication
- Critical Thinking

NITIN ADAM

RENEWABLE ENERGY AND BESS EXPERT

PROFILE

An Electrical Engineer with almost 6 Years of experience in the field of solar, wind, green hydrogen, microgrids & battery energy storage systems, strategic advisory, government advisory, policy and regulatory analysis, Net Zero strategy, open access, RE procurement strategy, financial implications under various business models, financial modelling, power system studies, design and consultancy for clean energy technologies, substations, Pre-bid/Basic/Detailed Engineering, project management, business consulting and bid evaluation for various renewable projects.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Tractebel Engineering Pvt. Ltd2024 - PRESENT
Senior Engineer (Transmission & Distribution)

KPMG, India 2022 - 2024

Consultant (Business Consulting - Strategy & Operations - Power & Utilities)

Tata Consulting Engineers, Ltd. 2019 - 2022 Senior Engineer (Renewable Energy - Power Business Unit)

EXPERTISE AREAS

- Techno-commercial Feasibility analysis of BESS using HOMER for different Business case
- Energy Mix study with various resources
- FEED Study for Solar, BESS and Wind
- · Landed cost of RE
- Financial Modelling for the estimation of LCOE / LCOS / Project IRR / EIRR
- Preparation of RFP/RFQ/RFI and responding back to technical clarification
- Policy and regulatory analysis
- RE procurement strategy
- Net Zero strategy
- RE procurement through Virtual PPA
- Preparation of Term Sheet, and PPA/SSA

- Policy Advocacy
- · Lenders Engineering
- Solar Resource & Energy Yield Assessment
- Pre-feasibility, feasibility & Detailed Report Preparation – Solar, Wind, BESS plants
- Root cause analysis for renewable plants
- · Balance of plant design engineering
- Basic engineering and BOQ preparation for solar PV, Wind and BESS Plants
- Substation design engineering up to 400kV level and protection systems
- Balanced Load Flow Study, Short Circuit Analysis using ETAP/PSSE
- · Green Hydrogen feasibility study
- · Value added engineering

SOFTWARE SKILLS

- HOMER Pro
- PLEXOS
- PVSyst
- ETAP
- PSS/E
- MATLAB
- DIALux
- ODYSSEY
- Google Earth
- MS-Office

PUBLICATIONS

"Performance Comparison of Two-Level Inverter with Classical Multilevel Inverter Topologies" has been published in IEEE explorer.



https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/doc ument/8869115?denied=

LANGUAGES

- English
- Hindi
- Marathi
- Telugu
- Kannada

PERSONAL DETAILS

- Date of Birth: 13-03-1998
- Marital Status: Single
- Gender: Male
- Interests: Reading, Carrom,
 Travelling, Learning, Research

KEY PROJECTS UNDERTAKEN

Battery Energy Storage Projects:

- Technical Advisory Services for the development of BESS Projects with total capacity of 2000MW/8000MWh each in KSA for SPPC
- Technical Advisory Services for the development of BESS Project with total capacity of 400MW/800MWh each in Abu Dhabi for EWEC
- Owner's Engineering Services for the development of hybrid Solar + BESS Plant to supply 300MW power from Indonesia to Singapore for Keppel
- Feasibility Study for Hybrid Solar + BESS Project in Philippines for ACEN
- Technical Advisory Services for BESS integrated with 100 MWac Solar Power Plant in Bangladesh for BEXIMCO
- Lender's Technical Advisory Services for 180MW/360MWh BESS in Gujarat, India for IndiGrid
- Lender's Technical Advisory Services for 24MWh BESS in four islands for Cabeolica
- Reactive Power Study for 1GW Solar PV with 100MW/200MWh BESS in Egypt for Scatec
- Technical assessment of BESS for 300 MW Wind & Solar PV Hybrid Plant, Gujarat, India for TUV Rheinland
- Pre-bid and basic engineering services for 60MW Solar PV+ 32MW/ 32MWh BESS project in GUAM islands
- · Feasibility Study of BESS for Tata Chemicals Ltd.
- Feasibility Study of Hybrid Solar+Wind+BESS plants to supply RTC power to Zinc Smelter Plant for Vendata

Solar PV Projects:

- Detailed engineering services for Adani 28 MW Mandamarri Solar PV Plant & 37 MW Kothagudem Solar PV plant, India
- Owner's engineering services for JSW 225 MW Solar PV Project in Bellary, Karnataka, India
- Owner's engineering services for Ayana 300 MW Solar PV Project in Bikaner, Rajasthan, India
- Owner's engineering services for Amplus 100 MW Solar PV Project in Deoria, Uttar Pradesh, India
- Owner's engineering services for BMM 20 MW Solar PV Plant in South Africa
- Root Cause Analysis for Skypower 50MW Solar PV Project in Madhya Pradesh, India
- Technical Advisory Services for ACWA 2.2GW Solar PV Plant integrated with 1.25GW Wind plant in Neom

Wind Projects:

- Technical Advisory services for ACWA Power 500 MW Wind Plant in Uzbekistan
- Technical Advisory services for ACWA Power 100 MW Wind Plant in Nukus
- Technical Advisory services for ACWA Power 250 MW Wind Plant in Azerbaijan

Green Hydrogen Projects:

- Techno-commercial Analysis of Green Hydrogen Plant in Oman for OQ
- Development of Methodology for the Implementation of Maharashtra Green Hydrogen Policy 2023

Substation Engineering Projects:

- Owner's Engineering Services for 261 MVA GIS Substation in Nepal for Nepal Electricity Authority
- Owner's Engineering Services for 165 MVA AIS Substation in India

Business Strategy Projects:

- RE procurement strategy for Amdocs in Pune, Maharashtra, India
- Development of Net Zero Strategy for MTN group in key African markets
- Bid Advisory & PPA execution in RE Procurement for HMEL, India
- Market Entry Strategy in Renewable Energy Segment in India for ITOCHU